{"questions" : [
	{"question": "Which of the following most closely resembles how today's executives view project management?", "a": "Project managers should be used for project execution only", "b": "Project management is a strategic or core competency necessary for the growth and survivability of the company", "c": "People must be certified in project management rather than business processes", "d": "Project managers are not responsible for bridging strategy and execution", "solution": "b"},
	{"question": "Project managers are now being brought on board projects:", "a": "After the project has been approved", "b": "At the Initiation of the project", "c": "After the business dase has been developed", "d": "After the project has been approved", "solution": "b"},
	{"question": "Metrics must be established for those activities that:", "a": "Are the most difficult to manage", "b": "The most difficult to measure", "c": "The most difficult to report", "d": "Have a direct bearing on the success or failure of the project", "solution": ""},
	{"question": "Which of the following is generally not part of a customer relations management program?", "a": "Identifying the right customers", "b": "Identifying the right metrics for each customer", "c": "Developing the right relationship with customers", "d": "Maintaining customer retention", "solution": "b"},
	{"question": "The most difficult part of stakeholder relations management is often:", "a": "Getting the stakeholders to agree to the goals and objectives of the project", "b": "Deciding who has influence and who has power", "c": "Identifying which stakeholders want the project to fail", "d": "Identifying which executives in your company will interface with the stakeholders", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "Which of the following is part of the difficulty in selecting metrics for the stakeholders?", "a": "Getting agreement on the metrics required", "b": "Determining if the metric data already exists in the system", "c": "Determining the cost of collecting the metric data and reporting the results", "d": "All of the above", "solution": "d"},
	{"question": "Which of the following audits are generally  performed by the PMO?", "a": "Metric and KPI audits", "b": "Best practices audits", "c": "Performance and compliance audits", "d": "All of the above", "solution": "d"},
	{"question": "Scope creep is not a natural occurence on projects and we must accept the fact that it will happen", "a": "True", "b": "False", "solution": "b"},
	{"question": "Scope creep can be considered as favorable if it provides add-ons that improve your competitive position or generate more business.", "a": "True", "b": "False", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "Scope creep caused by 'featuritis' is the result of:", "a": "Gold-plating a project and adding in unnecessary bells and whistles", "b": "Poor communications", "c": "Misunderstanding of expectations", "d": "Time-to-market pressure", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "In the early years, we discovered that:", "a": "Measurement of time and cost was usually quite accurate", "b": "The project was a success if we met the time and cost constraints", "c": "Unfavorable metrics did not often provide us with sufficient information for corrective action", "d": "Customers and stakeholders quickly understood the meaning of these metrics", "solution": "c"},
	{"question": "Which of the following did EVMS metrics address early on?", "a": "Unrealistic planning", "b": "Poor governance", "c": "Low quality of assigned resources", "d": "EVMS did not address any of these", "solution": "d"},
	{"question": "Which of the following drove the need for better metrics?", "a": "The desire for paperless project management", "b": "The growth in more complex projects", "c": "New definitions of project success and failure", "d": "All of the above", "solution": "d"},
	{"question": "Caper Jones, in his book, 'Assissment and Control of Software Risks', stated that the two major sources of IT failures were:", "a": "Inaccurate metrics and inadequate measurement techniques", "b": "Inaccurate metrics and poor governance", "c": "Poor governance and lack of user involvement", "d": "Lack of user involvement and insufficient time devoted to planning", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "Some metrics and KPIs may not be measured until well into the future because the measurement is base upon the beneficial use of the deliverable.", "a": "True", "b": "False", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "Which of the following is true", "a": "KPIs in one industry may not be transferable to another industry", "b": "KPIs in one company may not be transferable to another company even if they are both in the same industry", "c": "KPIs in one part of a business may not be transferable to another part of the business within the same company", "d": "All of the above", "solution": "d"},
	{"question": "In a project environment, uncertainty means that:", "a": "The risks may exceed a certain threshold level", "b": "You have limited knowledge about the future health of the project", "c": "Cost will increase and schedules will slip", "d": "There are no available measurement techniques", "solution": "b"},
	{"question": "Projects normally designed to imporve efficiency and effectivenes are classified as ____ projects", "a": "Enhancement or internal", "b": "Financial", "c": "Future-related", "d": "Customer-related", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "Long-term projects designed to create a down-stream cash flow are called ____ projects", "a": "Enhancement or internal", "b": "Financial", "c": "Future-related", "d": "Customer-related", "solution": "c"},
	{"question": "Which of the following benefits are easy to measure and convert into value?", "a": "Work force stability", "b": "Profitablity", "c": "Unused capacity", "d": "All of the above", "solution": "d"},
	{"question": "Which of the following benefits are hard to convert into value?", "a": "Image and reputation", "b": "Technology transfer", "c": "Development of new technology", "d": "Penetrating new markets", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "Which of the following factors may have a greater impact on the design of a dashboard for clients external to your company?", "a": "The need for drill-down capability", "b": "Summary versus detailed information", "c": "Summary information versus information needed for informed decision making", "d": "All of the above", "solution": "d"},
	{"question": "When designing a dashboard, the designers must 'reinvent the wheel', because each dashboard will have different requirements.", "a": "True", "b": "False", "solution": "b"},
	{"question": "The same metric may have to be displayed differently on two different dashboards even for audiendes within the same company because of the nature of different viewers.", "a": "True", "b": "False", "solution": "a"},
	{"question": "On a dashboard, the same metric may look fine from one perspective but indicate a problem when looked at from a different perspective.", "a": "True", "b": "False", "solution": "a"}
	]}